Dr. Khalifa: ... were swept in the crowd.
(unintelligible)
75 billion of us.
We did not make a firm stand with God or with Satan.
God sent us to see an invitation.
Dr. Khalifa: So, God knew that some of us in their heart knew that only God can be a god.
For Satan's contention that he could be a god was not only blasphemous, it was also wrong,
because it was not possible for anyone else to function as a god inside a dominion
and run it perfectly, without disease, without accidents, without problems.
Nobody can do that. (unintelligible). It was a wrong contention.
Being swept in the crowd, I'm gonna tell you about an experiment that some people did.
In this experiment, I think it was a very simple experiment.
There's an arrow like this with two heads.
(unintelligible)
And let's take two arrows, one of them has only one point, and the other has two points like that.
Now obviously, this one looks like this one, but this one does not.
So, the experiment was to get a group of people that let us agree that this arrow looks like this one.
And then, one member of the group was absent, and they said "let us, when he comes in, let's all say that this one looks like this one.
"And then ask him, which one of these two looks like this one?"
So, what happened?
So, when this fellow came in, they started to ask the question "which one of the two arrows looks like this one?"
And the group, one by one, said "this one looks like this one. This one here looks like this one."
Until they reached the fellow, the projected victim, and they told him, they asked him "which one of these two looks like this one?"
And he said "this one looks like this one."
He went along with the, with the crowd.
Now, you and I are sure that he knew that this one looked like this one.
In his heart, he knew that this one looked like this one.
But he probably said "maybe, they know something I don't know. Maybe, there's a trick here or something."
So, he went along with the crowd when he said "this one looks like this one."
This is a real-life experiment.
And this is precisely what happened in that Great Feud.
So, the angels suggested that all the creatures who did not oppose God's Absolute Authority must be thrown out.
And banished from God's Kingdom.
But because of God's knowledge that this fellow, in his heart, knew
which the correct answer is, he went along and was swept in the crowd,
some of us human beings were also swept in the crowd, and we,
we said "yeah, maybe, Satan can do it. Let us see a demonstration."
So, God wanted to give us a chance. God is Arrahman Arraheem.
He is the Most Merciful.
And He did not throw us out of His kingdom because of this crime that we committed, which is in fact the original sin.
He wanted to give us another chance to redeem ourselves, to denounce our crime, and to proclaim God's Absolute Authority and uphold it.
But only God can be a god.
Okay, this called for, for this second chance, a test was to be done in order for us to go through the same process.
In other words, if you, if you kept after this person and say "are you sure that this one looks like this one?"
He will say "yeah, I'm sure."
They will say "come on, think about it. This one has two pointers, but this has only one, but this has two pointers."
He will tell you, if you pressed him, he will say "well, I know that this one looks like this one, but everybody is saying this one looks like this one, so I thought maybe, maybe they know something I don't know."
So, this is the second chance.
For the second chance, we learn from Sura 67 that God created death. There was no death.
God created death.
All the creatures who did not uphold God's Absolute Authority are given a second chance, including the jinns and the humans
were, were put to death, and they were to be brought into this, this universe, which is the smallest and innermost of seven universes,
to be born into this world, having no recollection whatsoever of the Great Feud, or anything that happened in their first life.
The Quran calls it "the first life." And this is the second life.
No, excuse me, this is the first life after our death.
But we are born into this world without any recollection of what happened in the, in the Great Society.
And then, we are given a message from God, telling us "you shall uphold God's Absolute Authority."
We must worship only God, and we must know that God is the only One who possesses all power.
And we are also given a message from Satan.
Satan tells us "God alone is not enough. There are also other entities that can have power, like Muhammad, or Jesus, or Mary, or Saint Francis, or Imam Hussein."
I mean, this is what Satan has been pushing.
And then, we make a free-will decision to uphold God's Absolute Authority,
or repeat the crimes that we committed in the past, and we say "there can be other entities besides God who are powerful."
In other words, we're given another chance to go back to God's kingdom, or to join Satan's kingdom.
This is why we are here.
This is one of the main reasons for being here.
Now, this was the first half of the, of the answer that I talked about yesterday, and I want now to talk about the second half.
Second half is that, tragically, this being swept in the crowd is happening to, to many of us,
because the world is mostly oblivious to God.
People, those people driving out in the street, they are just going about their business totally oblivious to God.
And they don't do anything to, to develop their soul, nourish the, the real person.
They feed their bodies breakfast, lunch, and dinner.
But they totally neglect the real person.
They're feeding their bodies, the after-garment, this is the after-garment, and they leave the real person.
And some of us are being swept in the crowd.
We're doing the same thing as they are.
And if we decide to believe in God, even believe in God alone, that He alone is worthy of worship,
we don't do enough to develop our soul. because everybody else is not doing anything.
So, if one of us is doing only the Morning Prayer, some of us make funny statements like,
"Well, God should be happy I'm doing the Morning Prayer. Look at all those people doing nothing. I'm doing the Morning Prayer every morning."
But this is, it is not enough.
It is again the, it's repeating the mistake, the original mistake, being swept in the crowd.
But the Quran teaches us, in order to be saved, to be redeemed, and to go back to God's Kingdom,
we have to set a minimum for our salvation.
A minimum amount of, I'm getting to call it gifts now, that we must give ourselves.
We, we grew up taking these obligations, like the Five Daily Prayers.
We've, we've grown accustomed to call them duties.
And they, they changed into something like chores.
So, somehow Satan succeeded in, in convincing us that these are chores, or duties that we must do for God, in order to be saved.
This is all wrong.
They are not chores.
They're not duties or obligations. The Quran teaches that they are gifts from God.
And when you do the Five Daily Prayers, God has given you a gift because you deserve it,
and because He knew that in your heart, you knew that this one looks like this one, deep in your heart,
even though you said with your mouth that "yes, Satan can do it."
So, He gives you this gift. And we see it in the Quran when the prophet Abraham prays. He says,
(14:40) رَبِّ ٱجْعَلْنِى مُقِيمَ ٱلصَّلَوٰةِ
This is what he prayed for.
When we pray now, we pray for health, or wealth, or "please God make my kids receive (unintelligible) or something."
But he prayed and he said "please God make me one who observes the Contact Prayers" because it's a gift from God.
Because they are the meals for the real person, five meals a day.
All of us were very careful to make sure that "I'm gonna have lunch today" which is not really the case.
I'm not gonna have lunch today, I'm gonna give my body lunch today.
But if we realize that the Five Daily Prayers, for example, are a gift from God, we will
we will be glad, we will be eager to, to feed our souls, just like we are eager to feed our bodies.
So, let me go through this minimum...
This will be the minimum for any believer in order to avoid being swept in the crowd.
This is the Five Contact Prayers.
The second item I put here is Zakat.
It will not be surprising that 99% of us right here in this room do not give the Zakat.
And just to scare you a little bit, the Quran, Allah Subhanahu Wa Ta'ala tells us that He's going to restrict His mercy to those who give Zakat.
The verse says, It says,
(7:156) وَرَحْمَتِى وَسِعَتْ كُلَّ شَىْءٍۢ
[7:156] ... My mercy encompasses all things. ...
This is what God said.
(7:156) وَرَحْمَتِى وَسِعَتْ كُلَّ شَىْءٍۢ
[7:156] ... My mercy encompasses all things. ...
(7:156) فَسَأَكْتُبُهَا لِلَّذِينَ يَتَّقُونَ وَيُؤْتُونَ ٱلزَّكَوٰةَ
But I will restrict it for those who are righteous, who give the Zakat.
That's how important this item is, number two, Zakat, the charity.
And this is repeated in the Quran so many times.
They ask the people in Hell "Why are you here?"
They say "we didn't feed the poor."
One of the answers.
In fact, it is "we didn't observe the Contact Prayer, and we didn't feed the poor."
(74:42) مَا سَلَكَكُمْ فِى سَقَرَ (74:43) قَالُوا۟ لَمْ نَكُ مِنَ ٱلْمُصَلِّينَ
We did not do the Five Prayers.
(74:44) وَلَمْ نَكُ نُطْعِمُ ٱلْمِسْكِينَ
And [74:44] "We did not feed the poor.
So, these are the two most important... These have to be minimum for you.
The Five, you must make a determination that you must feed your soul the five basic meals.
Why I'm on this subject of the five basic meals?
The Quran, you see it in my new translation, the theme of the new translation is right here.
This is, this is in the text.
It will not be this big, so don't worry because this is only one side.
As soon as you open the front cover, you're gonna see this theme here, which says,
[2:62] Surely, those who believe, those who are Jewish, the Christians, the converts; anyone who (1) believes in GOD , and (2) believes in the Hereafter, and (3) leads a righteous life, will receive their recompense from their Lord. They have nothing to fear, nor will they grieve.
So, the Jews, the Christians, the Hindus, the Buddhists, the Muslims, anyone who believes in God,
this means God alone, and believes in the Hereafter, and leads a righteous life, they have nothing to fear.
Now, when we read other verses in the Quran, so how does this fit with the Five Contact Prayers?
Because the Jews or the Christians don't do the Five Contact Prayers, or the Buddhists or Hindus.
But if they satisfy these three requirements, they will be saved.
But how does this fit with this other verse in the Quran tell us
that anything righteous they do, they are rewarded for it.
But it will be like living on snacks.
It will be a slow process.
It will be like going from here to there without a map, or going from San Francisco to Dallas, Texas, without a map.
The Five Contact Prayers are the fastest way of developing your soul, our soul.
And we do learn this from the Quran, that these righteous people will make it, but
they will not make it to the degree, or the rank, or the extent, that you can make it using the five basic Prayers.
It's exactly like living on snacks for the body.
You give your bodies potato chips, and sunflower seeds, all day, a piece of candy, and, but no basic meal, no main meal.
This will start to grow.
You will not be healthy.
But you still will survive not for a long time, either.
So, the Five Contact Prayers here are the five basic meals for the soul.
The Zakat, we thank God for teaching us how to do it right, because everywhere in the Muslim world, they do it wrong.
The majority of Muslims in the world, they give the Zakat, if they do, once a year.
2.5% of their savings that are one-year-old, about the same (unintelligible).
But this is what the Quran says, this is what God says.
Sura 6, verse 141. God says "you must give the Zakat on the day of harvest."
And we don't harvest wheat or beans. We only harvest checks.
This is what we harvest, our salary, or our income from trading, from an investment, or a sale.
But the, the principle is that any time we receive money, that will go into your pocket, that's your money, your money.
You must leave, set aside at least 2.5% of that, and give it away to a specific set of recipients in the Quran.
And they are in this order: your parents.
If they are rich, then you go to your relatives, your cousins, your sisters, brothers, nephews, nieces, aunts, uncles.
This is the second category.
Number 3, (unintelligible) the orphans.
If you have some orphans, they have no support from a parent or both parents.
(2:215) وَٱلْمَسَٰكِينِ وَٱبْنِ ٱلسَّبِيلِ
The poor, any poor (unintelligible) after that.
And the next category is the traveling alien.
Somebody just came from Mexico and they don't have a job, and they are working on their immigration papers,
they don't have, they cannot work, they don't have a work permit.
This is the next category.
But the Zakat must be given on, on your net income, 2.5%, immediately.
When you read the Quran, we see that Zakat and Salat, Salat, NAMAZ and Zakat are together, always, as if they are a daily process.
In fact, the very, the first, first page of the Quran.
In Sura Al-Baqarah, Sura number 2, not the first page, but the second page.
Definition of the Righteous
They observe the Contact Prayers, and spend from our provisions to them, which is these two, Salat and Zakat.
Right at the beginning of the Quran, these two points are mentioned.
These are the minimum, number one and two are minimum sets.
By the way, the Zakat, as it is practiced in the Muslim world is not, it doesn't make sense.
Because if you have a theoretical calculation of something, let's say you have 40 million dollars, and, in the savings,
you give 2.5% of that, a million dollars.
And then the following year, you have to give Zakat again, you have 39 million dollars left.
The following year, you have to give another million dollars. It's not fair.
According to the Quran, when you give the million dollars out of the 40 million, you already purified these 40 million. They are yours.
You are clean. And you no longer have to give Zakat again.
According to the so-called Islamic system, you have to give until you're broke.
And Zakat (unintelligible) goes on, until you're broke.
(unintelligible)
2.5%, one time.
From anything when you receive it.
At the time you receive it.
Dr. Khalifa: Ok. Number 3 is that...
A woman: Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: The Fasting we're doing in the month of Ramadan.
And this, this goes a long way towards developing your soul.
Dr. Khalifa: Because Siyam, Siyam, ROOZE, ROOZE, ROOZE?
A woman (Speaking Farsi): ROOZE (Fasting)
Dr. Khalifa: ROOZE (Fasting) during the month of Ramadan.
Because every day in Ramadan, you're telling your body "you're not gonna eat or drink until sunset."
So, this, this straightens you.
So, God gave us a wild horse. This body is a wild horse. We are supposed to tame it.
So, God gave us the means to tame it and control it.
Also, it's a measure of your degree of development.
This will take me back to the Prayers, the Five Contact Prayers.
Because you can measure your degree of development by, for example, the Morning Prayer, which is before sunrise.
It is very good for you physically, also.
You will not develop arthritis if you do wake up every morning before sunrise.
I used to say this on a theoretical basis until I heard the advertisement.
Maybe, you also heard this from the Arthritis Foundation.
It says "do not stay in, in the same position, sit in the same position for a long time."
Some truck driver was asking "what do I do? I have arthritis."
And they said "every few hours you must get out and stretch."
Now, when we go to sleep and we, we sit like that, the joints become stiff. They need to be lubricated.
So, God does not want to bother us and annoy us by asking us to get up before sunrise every day.
He doesn't need us to do that.
We need it.
So, if we do the Morning Prayer...
I'm sorry I (unintelligible), but this is the physical part of it.
If you get up and lubricate your joints, and you will not have arthritis when you grow up, (unintelligible).
The spiritual part of it is you can measure the degree of your development.
Because as you become strong, you, not the body, you become strong, your body will become obedient to you.
So, you can measure if, if you wake up...
If you cannot wake up at all in the morning, you are in bad shape.
You cannot tell your body to get up for your own good, for the morning meal, the Morning Prayer before sunrise.
Because there is a fight between you and your body every morning.
If you, if you decide to do this, there comes tomorrow morning before sunrise and the body wants to sleep.
But you need, you need to, to make it wake up.
So, this struggle takes place and one of you wins, either you or your body.
If the body wins, you continue to sleep. And you will continue to be weak.
If you win, you will grow and you develop and the growth of the soul is very fast.
Sura 17
It says "the growth..."
See, we grow until we're 5 feet or 6 feet tall.
But the soul grows until it is bigger than San Francisco, the soul, your soul.
So, the degree of growth is, the gain is fantastic.
It's not like, you know, we eat this food to grow and we're very limited in growth, the body is.
But the soul grows immensely.
So, if you succeed in, in forcing your body to get up before sunrise and do the Morning,
make contact with your Creator before sunrise, you grow a lot.
So, at first, it will be difficult.
But in a month or two, you will grow sufficiently that when you say to your body "get up and do the Morning Contact Prayer", it will get up grudgingly.
And this will show you another, the degree of your growth.
You will be on your way.
It will be very good but then even though your body is getting up grudgingly to do the Contact Prayer, it's very good.
Better than saying "no" and losing to your body.
But gradually as you grow stronger, your body will become absolutely obedient to you.
This will tell you how much growth you attained.
There comes a time before sunrise to set the alarm. In fact, you will not need to set the alarm anymore.
This is true. You will not need it.
You will wake up your body at the right time before sunrise to get up to do the Contact Prayer.
And your body obediently will, will start to enjoy.
And this will tell you at what degree, where you stand.
And eventually, you will really enjoy. You will be enjoying the Morning Prayer.
You will be very cheerful. Most people get up in the morning and have a long face.
But you'll get up with a big smile every morning before sunrise.
So, this will provide you with a yardstick as to the degree of your growth.
Now, Fasting does the same thing.
Because first thing in the morning, your body wants breakfast.
And you issue a command to your body. "No, I'm not gonna eat or drink not until sunset."
And this will cause you to grow and develop.
So, God designed these things.
Zakat also (unintelligible) you're taking, not your money, but most people love very much, and you give it away.
So, you can see that all these are designed for, for our benefit to make our souls grow and develop.
These are gifts from God.
And if you are fortunate to receive the gift, you will do these things.
It seems like what it takes is a decision.
You decide that you want to worship God alone.
Then, God will give you these gifts and you'll be able to do it.
So, your part is really very easy. All you need to do is a decision.
"I want to be redeemed. I want to be with God alone."
"I believe that Muhammad, Jesus, Mary, Hussein, Ali, none of them has any power."
"Only God has all power."
So, the question, this is all you need, a decision.
And God, you'll see that you do these things automatically.
The fourth minimum, we call it ZIKR (ذکر).
I just wrote it ZIKR (ذکر).
But I have to explain it.
In the Quran, there's a commandment, in the Quran, that's very important that says,
(33:41) يَٰٓأَيُّهَا ٱلَّذِينَ ءَامَنُوا۟ [33:41] O you who believe...
(33:41) ٱذْكُرُوا۟ ٱللَّهَ ذِكْرًۭا كَثِيرًۭا [33:41] ... remember GOD continuously.*
A lot. Frequently.
And this is not any ritual or anything that you perform. It's something that you do continuously.
You look at this view and say "Subhan Allah." God be glorified.
You realize God's creation, the beauty that God created in the world.
You look at the fruit.
Look how many flavors we have here.
When I say the word "orange", you think of a certain flavor.
Then, I say "strawberry."
And you think of a certain flavor.
Strawberry has a color, texture, taste, flavor, smell.
And these are all chemicals that God created in the strawberry.
There is peach.
(unintelligible)
So, when you look at this, you say, "Subhan Allah."
And God didn't have to do all this.
But this is ZIKR (ذکر).
When we say "Subhan Allah", we think of God's creation and God's Greatness.
This is what we do with ZIKR (ذکر).
But let me start from the beginning.
The minimum that you want to set for yourself is starts when you wake up in the morning.
The first thing you must say in the morning must be the name of God, first thing you say.
In this country, most people start with a dirty word in the morning, every morning, when the alarm goes off.
You want to start with the name of God.
Bism Allah Arrahman Arraheem
La Elaha Ella Allah
There is no god except the One God.
It's gonna take you three or four months if you're not doing it already, it's gonna take you three or four months, at least, to get used to it.
The first thing you do when you open up your eyes.
This is ZIKR (ذکر).
Because what you utter, the first thing you say in the morning, every morning, this is
what you'll utter when you get up on the Day of Resurrection.
The real life, the eternal life, that will determine your rank forever.
And you don't wanna utter a dirty word on the Day of Resurrection.
So, this is the first thing we do, and of course, we do the Morning Prayer.
There are certain commandments in the Quran, straightforward commandments, that you must do to carry out this, this gift.
For example, in Sura 18, God says "Do not say, I will do anything without saying IN SHAA ALLAH", saying "God willing."
It says,
(18:23) لَا تَقُولَنَّ لِشَا۟ىْءٍ Do not say about anything
(18:23) إِنِّى فَاعِلٌ ذَٰلِكَ غَدًا I'm doing this tomorrow
(18:24) إِلَّآ أَن يَشَآءَ ٱللَّهُ without saying IN SHAA ALLAH.
You must never say "I'm gonna see you tomorrow" and that's it.
You must say "I'll see you tomorrow, God willing."
Even when you work with Americans, or non-Muslims, at first, you'll be shy, they're (unintelligible) to say "what is this?"
And they will say that. They'll be taken aback when you say "God willing",
but eventually, they will respect you, and they will get used to it, and you'll be carrying out your duty.
You're actually reminding the people of their Creator.
Say "I'm gonna finish this at 6 o'clock, God willing.
And it must become a habit. Again, it'll take 3 or 4 months,
but this is a commandment in the Quran.
"Do not say, I will do anything without saying 'IN SHAA ALLAH.'"
The Quran gives you a commandment, also, that if you want to invoke protection for your children, for example,
or your car, or your property, you must say "Mã Shã Allãh."
This is Sura 18, also.
(unintelligible)
This man who lost his garden.
God says "if only when you entered your garden, you said 'Mã Shã Allãh.' The complete statement is
(18:39) مَا شَآءَ ٱللَّهُ لَا قُوَّةَ إِلَّا بِٱللَّهِ
you would not have lost your garden.
So, this tells us that in order to invoke protection for your own children, your own property, your own car,
you say "Mã Shã Allãh." You start your car and starts like that, very nicely, you say "Mã Shã Allãh."
Now, before you start, say "Bismillah." (unintelligible)
This is what ZIKR (ذکر) is.
You must seek every chance to mention God.
This is because we came to the realization, and this is very important, that your god... who's your god?
Let me stop you and ask you a question. Don't answer me.
It's in your mind. In your mind.
In your mind, answer me. Who is your god?
So, every one of you is saying "my god is the Creator of the heavens and the earth."
And most of you are wrong.
Shocked, we were shocked when we came to this realization.
Two times. When we came to this realization, and I was speaking and writing sermons.
We were all shocked, because we examined ourselves as to who is our god.
Because it turns out, when you study the Quran carefully, that your god
is whoever or whatever occupies your mind most of the day.
And we examined ourselves, and we found that the Creator of the heavens and the earth was not our god.
We thought we were believers, and we thought our god was the Creator of the heavens and the earth.
And this would have been the, and this is the answer that the Quran gives, describing many people, who are headed, going, going to Hell.
At the end of Sura 23, for example, "if you ask them, who is the Lord of the heavens and the earth, and the Lord of the great dominion?"
(23:86) قُلْ مَن رَّبُّ ٱلسَّمَٰوَٰتِ ٱلسَّبْعِ وَرَبُّ ٱلْعَرْشِ ٱلْعَظِيمِ (23:87) سَيَقُولُونَ لِلَّهِ ۚ قُلْ أَفَلَا تَتَّقُونَ
Why are you...
[23:89] ... "Where did you go wrong?"
So, here, they are saying "God, the Lord of the heavens and the earth."
But you see, they are saying it with their mouth, and this is the answer with their mouth,
but they are preoccupied with other things.
Therefore, this is why the commandment to "remember constantly", is very important.
At least, 51% of the day.
And it's very easy, I know you're thinking, "how can I come? I'm at work, I'm busy with the computer, and so on. How can I think of God?"
It's really very easy, because when you're go to the computer, you look, and you see somebody put a flower on the desk or something,
you see flowers on your desk.
You look at the design of the flower, you say "Subhan Allah." God be glorified.
This will satisfy (unintelligible).
This is why it will interrupt your, your thinking and concentration of the world,
and you'll, you'll, you'll think of God.
By the way, I'll go back to the Contact Prayers.
The Five Contact Prayers go a long way, towards, this, remembering God.
As a matter of fact, if you look at Sura 20, verse 14, God says,
[20:14] ... observe the Contact Prayers (Salat) to remember Me.
(20:14) وَأَقِمِ ٱلصَّلَوٰةَ لِذِكْرِىٓ
(unintelligible)
This is the reason, for giving you this gift, is to cause you to remember God, because it is not just the two minutes,
you know, we went back there and prayed the Afternoon Prayer, two minutes.
It is not just those two minutes, that are counted in your favor, as credit for you.
Two hours ago, we looked at the watch, and we said "oh, it's not the Afternoon Prayer yet."
See, that's remembering God then, and this goes to the credit.
And an hour later, we said "oh, is it time for the Afternoon Prayer? No, it is not."
So, you're thinking of God. What is the Afternoon Prayer? You're doing it, you're not doing it to get a salary, or to be paid.
You're doing it for God, and just thinking about it.
So, the Five Prayers, when you go to sleep, you say "I hope I get up before sunrise tomorrow, to pray the Morning Prayer."
So, that, that is it.
The Five Prayers every day, this is why the most important minimum gift for your soul is the Five Prayers.
They go a long way.
Soul's making the Creator of the heavens and the earth, your god,
and not your job, or your spouse, or your children, or your property.
These are the gods and are counted in the Quran.
The gods, that are counted in the Quran, include spouses, a man who worships his wife, instead God,
or a wife who worships her husband, instead of God.
Children, giving more attention to our children, than to God.
These are also counted as gods. Sura 7.
Sura 7, there's a verse, you probably remember it, that says, that the wife becomes pregnant,
and the load becomes heavier and heavier, and then, they pray to God "please God, give us a good baby."
And then, as soon as He gives them a good baby, they turn the baby into a god besides God.
Sura 7, very clear.
At the Sura 18, the person who lost his garden, his garden was his god. His property, his business, his job.
The ego is another god, Sura 25.
The ego can stop you from being saved.
The ego, NAFS (نفس).
So, in order, the Five Prayers, and this ZIKR (ذکر) will help you, as to who your god is.
The, the Creator of the heavens and earth will be your god through this ZIKR (ذکر).
It's a very important commandment.
(33:41) يَٰٓأَيُّهَا ٱلَّذِينَ ءَامَنُوا۟ ٱذْكُرُوا۟ ٱللَّهَ ذِكْرًۭا كَثِيرًۭا
(33:42) وَسَبِّحُوهُ بُكْرَةًۭ وَأَصِيلًا
Make TASBIH (تسبیح) day and night.
Day and night, make TASBIH (تسبیح).
This is how we, this is how we get saved.
And then, when I asked you "who is your god?" and you might say "the Creator of the heavens and the earth", you will be right.
Only through this. Through ZIKR (ذکر).
As it is, when we examined ourselves, some time ago, and we discovered that we flunked,
that the Creator of the heavens and the earth was not our god.
We were preoccupied with other things.
Then, we set the minimum, the minimum, of ZIKR (ذکر).
First thing in the morning, the Five Prayers.
You look at your child, and you say "Mã Shã Allãh", meaning, God gave you this... this is God's gift to me.
And this immediately, invokes protection, for you and your child.
There's a mechanism for it. It's very physical.
Because when you say "Mã Shã Allãh", immediately, angels will guard your child.
Your child can go, ride the bicycle, and go between the traffic, and an (unintelligible)
(unintelligible)
But yes, your child will be protected, (unintelligible) anywhere.
So, there's a mechanism for it when you say "Mã Shã Allãh."
So, IN SHAA ALLAH is a commandment.
When we say "I'm gonna do" anything in the future, you must say "IN SHAA ALLAH."
Mã Shã Allãh.
Subhan Allah. Anytime. Alhamdu Lillah.
Oh, there is a commandment that says "do not eat from anything upon which the name of God was not pronounced."
And, although I tend to think this applies to meat, I think it applies to eggs, and peaches, and oranges.
So, before you eat, say "Bismillah."
Take that. Before you start anything, before you start your car, say "Bismillah."
These, these are all just chances that we must grab to, to make God, our god,
and not our job, or our business, or our children, and so on.
Cause this will give you everything else.
This will guarantee you your job, it will guarantee you your children, it will guarantee you your spouse, and so on.
So, this is, I would say this, this opinion may be number one.
The Contact Prayers go a long way towards that.
Now, the idea behind all this is we don't want to repeat the mistake that we did in the past.
Billions of years ago.
We don't wanna be swept in the crowd.
It doesn't matter if the people around you do not do the Five Prayers. You do them.
And don't be, don't let Sheytan (Satan) tell you "oh, God should be happy that you do one Prayer." "I'm doing the Morning Prayer, so that should be enough. I'm better than all these people."
Yes, you are, but it's not enough.
You're not giving yourself the, the proper meal.
So, I think I will stop at this and let the questions or the discussions together remind me that we forgot anything.
And this is the basic idea as to why we are here.
We thank God that He let us know first why we are here.
He gave us a very sharp, clear picture to our generation.
We wouldn't know this 20 years ago if we were born 20 years earlier.
We wouldn't, we wouldn't know this.
God let us know that we were doing everything wrong.
Everything we were doing, everything we grew up doing was wrong.
The NAMAZ (Salat) was wrong. The Zakat was wrong. The Fasting was wrong. The Hajj was wrong.
We neglected the ZIKR (ذکر).
And God, out of His mercy and grace, He taught us the correct way to do it.
So, we have to, right now, we should turn to God mentally and thank Him for showing us the right way,
and at the same time make a pledge that we will rejoin God's kingdom.
(unintelligible) to ourselves.
Dr. Khalifa: (unintelligible)
A woman: Hajj (unintelligible) one time?
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, once, once in a lifetime.
Dr. Khalifa: Hajj, your husband can afford it. A woman: (unintelligible).
Not until you save enough money.
And do as much shopping.
Dr. Khalifa: Then, (unintelligible) you can make Hajj. Yes.
A woman: IN SHAA ALLAH.
Dr. Khalifa: I didn't talk about Hajj here because it's once in a lifetime, but
people who perform Hajj destroy it by going to the prophet Muhammad's mosque and they go and commit idol worship as a tomb.
A destroyed Hajj.
They were destroying NAMAZ (Salat) by mentioning the names of Muhammad, 'Al-e Muhammad, Ibrahim, 'Al-e Ibrahim in the Salat.
So, what is happening now is that God is purifying all these things for us. We must be devoted to God alone.
But Sheytan (Satan) will always push somebody to be mentioned somebody next to God.
In fact, the first pillar of Islam is gonna, the traditional five pillars, is what is called Shahadah.
It is stated in the Quran as "La Elaha Ella Allah" or "Ash-hadu Alla Elaha Ella Allah."
Sura 3, verse 18.
(3:18) شَهِدَ ٱللَّهُ أَنَّهُۥ لَآ إِلَٰهَ إِلَّا هُوَ
This is the Shahadah.
Now, when we grew up, they told us "the Shahadah is "Ash-hadu Alla Elaha Ella Allah Wa Ash-hadu Anna Muhammadan Rasulallah."
Now, this destroys the Shahadah.
The first commandment in the Bible, the Old Testament, the New Testament, the Quran is "La Elaha Ella Allah."
When you add another name, it's not what Muhammad wants.
It's what Sheytan (Satan) wants.
And as a matter of fact, the Quran says that only the hypocrites will say "Ash-hadu Alla Elaha Ella Allah Wa Ash-hadu Anna Muhammadan Rasulallah."
Dr. Khalifa: Go ahead.
A woman: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: It's very good question. It's very good question. We did do this earlier today.
In Sura 73, God says "commemorate God two-thirds of the night, one-third of the night, or one half of the night."
It's all in the Sura.
[73:3] ... little less. [73:4] Or a little more. ...
Ok. Now, we have to understand that the night in the Quran begins at sunset.
And also in the Torah, in all the scriptures.
The night begins at sunset and ends at sunrise.
Now, if you do the Five Contact Prayers, you'll satisfy this requirement.
Because you're gonna do the Sunset Prayer at 7 o'clock.
You're gonna do the Night Prayer at 9 o'clock or 9:30.
And you're gonna do the Dawn Prayer at 5 o'clock in the morning.
So, from 7 to 10, that is 3 hours at the beginning of the night.
And from 5 to 7, that's 2 hours in the morning.
That's 5 hours, that's already 4:30 to 9:30.
Almost half night.
This is what it means.
If you misunderstand it, you will get up in the middle of the night, and you will find yourself in a strange state.
If you misunderstand it.
But if you do the Five Prayers, you will...
Also in addition to the Five Prayers, there is a strong recommendation in Sura 17 to read the Quran at dawn.
So, you get up before sunrise, and you do the Morning Prayer, and read the Quran.
Dr. Khalifa: And this will satisfy the requirement (unintelligible).
A woman: I have a question about social justice. If you're using of your time through Zakat, trying to change oppressive conditions or
A woman: trying to alleviate suffering, is that a form of giving?
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. A woman: Working for justice?
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Of course, there is no substitute for Zakat.
Zakat is a very specific gift from God, which has to do with your income, money.
Any time you receive money that becomes yours, you must take out 2.5% and give it away to the people in the (unintelligible).
But giving up from your time, for social justice, and all other things, and all the... it's called Sadaqa (صدقه).
It's another name for charity. But there's a system behind it.
Dr. Khalifa: You had a question.
A woman: Did you believe in any other power besides God leading us?
Dr. Khalifa: Any idols?
A woman: Any other power? A woman: Other power?
Dr. Khalifa: Power beside God leading us? No.
Dr. Khalifa: There's no other power in the universe.
A woman: So, why do we have to...
A woman: If we, I mean already, He, I mean He's leading us, why do we have to ZIKR him all the time?
Dr. Khalifa: Because you can give it up.
Dr. Khalifa: You can give up God's power and God's protection.
A woman: He doesn't need that, does He?
Dr. Khalifa: No, He doesn't need it. A woman: We need it.
Dr. Khalifa: It's all, all for us.
None of this is for God.
This is why God created the earth in this way.
What way?
Our universe has a billion galaxies.
One billion galaxies.
But let me start from here, the solar system.
The solar system is very small compared to the rest of our universe.
And it is 2 billion miles across.
Dr. Khalifa: 2 billion miles across.
A woman: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: No. Miles. The solar system.
Solar system (unintelligible). The light comes up from the sun in 8 minutes. 93 million miles away.
The sun is 93 million miles away. That's a long distance.
So, the light takes 8 minutes to come here from the sun.
The solar system is 32 million miles across.
The solar system is a very small component of the galaxy, the Milky Way galaxy.
The Milky Way galaxy is 100,000 light years across. I'm not talking about miles anymore.
100,000. We travel at the speed of light. Imagine. Sun, 93 million miles. The light comes in 8 minutes.
We cross the Milky Way galaxy in 100,000 light years. At the speed of light. 100,000 years.
Dr. Khalifa: There are 1 million of these galaxies. 1 billion. Excuse me.
Behrouz: [54:2] Yet, whenever they see a sign, they turn away saying, "This is real magic."
[54:3] They disbelieved, and followed their own opinions, and what they've seen, physically seen
[54:4] They have received enough knowledge to set them straight.
[54:5] Great wisdom had come to them; but the warnings seem to be useless.
[54:6] Therefore, leave them alone; the day will come when the caller calls them to something terrible.
[54:7] Their eyes will be tumbled. Say, they come out of their graves like a swarm of locusts.
Dr. Khalifa: Very good. I don't want to waste your time by asking him for evidence, or proof,
that somebody paid me or somebody else millions of dollars to destroy the Sunnah of the prophet.
Dr. Khalifa: Because "Sallallahu Alaihi Wasallam" you said. Are you aware that God makes Salat for all the believers?
A man (Speaking Arabic): (33:56) إِنَّ ٱللَّهَ وَمَلَٰٓئِكَتَهُۥ يُصَلُّونَ عَلَى ٱلنَّبِىِّ
Edip: Why don't you say Salat to me too? Dr. Khalifa: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: So, why don't you, when I mentioned Hadith and say "Sallallahu Alaihi Wasallam"?
Edip: Yes, please pray for me, too.
A man: I know.
A man: I know, I pray for all Muslims.
A man: When Muhammad called people (unintelligible) "Sallallahu Alaika Wasallam" When called everybody "(unintelligible) Sallallahu Alaika Wasallam",
A man: But if your intention, you see, if your intention is clean, Dr. Khalifa: (unintelligible)
A man: in other word, the word will be for your intention.
A man: But if your intention is dirty to make people turn their back away from the Sunnah of Rasulullah, that's not nice.
Dr. Khalifa: But is lying Sunnah of the prophet? Did the prophet lie?
A man: Never.
Dr. Khalifa: So, why do you lie?
A man: I never lie.
Dr. Khalifa: You said that I received millions of dollars to (unintelligible).
A man: I said my feeling. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: I never said, I have a proof. Otherwise, I will show it to anybody.
A man: (unintelligible).
A man: In my heart. A man: (unintelligible) people's mind. For example, you said something like that
Dr. Khalifa: Ok, then, you are aware. A man: (unintelligible) in my mind (unintelligible) Ok?
A man: It's a big sin because you are going to, For example, you don't know anything about that one.
A man: But if you change my mind, Ok?
Dr. Khalifa: Simple.
A man: But you try to... Dr. Khalifa: Let me, let me, I have a question.
Dr. Khalifa: Are you aware, are you aware of the Quranic law that says,
(49:12) إِنَّ بَعْضَ ٱلظَّنِّ إِثْمٌۭ
[49:12] ... a little bit of suspicion is sinful. ...
Dr. Khalifa: So, you are here, is it a Sunnah of the prophet to commit sin? To be suspicious?
A man: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: So, why do you suspect that I took millions of dollars to (unintelligible)?
A man: Because of what you're doing. Your doing itself, it's a clear sign to me that they stopped fighting the Quran,
A man: and now they are fighting the Sunnah.
Dr. Khalifa: So, what did you prove? What is, what is the sign that I have millions of dollars?
A woman: (unintelligible)
A man: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Was Muhammad Sunni or Shia?
A man: Muhammad was not Sunni, was not Shia.
A woman: So, how come you are Sunni?
A man: I am not Sunni myself. I am not Sunni.
A woman: (unintelligible) you are Sunni. A man: I follow, I follow...
A woman: You change even (unintelligible) A man: (unintelligible)
A woman: (unintelligible) sorry A woman: Allahu Akbar
A man: I am following the Sunnah of Rasulullah.
A woman: You are Sunni. A man: I am not Sunni.
A man: I am not Shia. I am Muslim.
A man: My brother...
Dr. Khalifa: Ok, (unintelligible)
Ok. Let us read the Al-Fãtehah and ask God to, to protect us from Sheytan (Satan).
We are, we are begging Allah Subhanahu Wa Ta'ala to protect us from Sheytan (Satan), to make our worship, devotion, study and everything
devoted to Allah alone, in accordance with His word, the Quran.
Al-Fãtehah
Bism Allah Arrahman Arraheem (1:1) Al hamdu Lillahi Rabbil ‘Alameen (1:2) Arrahman Arraheem (1:3) Maliki Yawm Eddeen (1:4) Eyyaka Na’abudu Wa Eyyaka Nasta’aeen (1:5) Ehdina Al-Serata Al-Mustaqeem (1:6) Serata Al-Lazeena An’amta ‘Alayhim Ghayri Al-Maghdoobi ‘Alayhim Wa Laddaalleen (1:7)
(unintelligible)
Let us go back to our regular program with
Dr. Khalifa: with any questions and the things that we (unintelligible)
A man: Now, does the Zakat, if you give the Zakat to your family, if they're non-believers, does that matter?
A man: (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: No, it doesn't matter.
Dr. Khalifa: God did not say, give it to your believing parents. A man: Ok.
Dr. Khalifa: (unintelligible)
A woman: I have a question.
A woman: Let's say I'm sending my sister to college.
A woman: Is that, is that Zakat?
Dr. Khalifa: Well, you have to calculate. See, Zakat has to be calculated.
So, I receive this income, 2.5% is this much, and then I give it to sister who's going to college
and add more if you want because the 2.5% is the minimum.
You can add any more. And yes. The answer is yes.
Dr. Khalifa: You can, you can consider it. A woman: So, that is automatically Zakat?
Dr. Khalifa: No, it's not automatically Zakat. You have to have the intention.
You have to be aware that you are taking a proportion of your income to give to your sister as Zakat.
You cannot inadvertently pray the Noon Prayer because
you have to make the intention and do the Noon Prayer.
And Zakat is exactly the same thing.
The Prayer is a specific thing to do, and you must have the intention to do it.
Dr. Khalifa: So, as long as you specifically make the intention that you are giving the Zakat to your sister, then the requirement is satisfied.
A woman: How about your children? Dr. Khalifa: The same.
Dr. Khalifa: Well,... A woman: to give Zakat?
Dr. Khalifa: No, no, the children are your duty to raise them.
A man: And what if they don't live in?
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, that's different. They are independent persons, right?
Dr. Khalifa: They will fall under Aqrabin (أَقْرَبِينَ), the relatives.
A woman: This is a verse in the Quran that it says that all the fruits are male or female. Where is that?
A woman: I don't know. I couldn't find it though.
Dr. Khalifa: (unintelligible)
A man: Kinds.
A woman: All the kinds of fruits.
A woman: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: No, (unintelligible) Zojain (زَوْجَيْنِ)
Dr. Khalifa: Everything is in pairs.
A woman: Even fruits?
Dr. Khalifa: Even the atom, not the atom. There's the neutron and proton.
I mean, there is a positive or negative.
Dr. Khalifa: Electron and proton. Edip: 13, chapter 13 (unintelligible)
Edip: If you want, let me if you want for (unintelligible)
A woman: Thank you.
A man: Excuse me. (unintelligible) that at the beginning (unintelligible) that us being in heaven and earth.
A man: (unintelligible) I have question.
A man: I wanna know if God knew that us (unintelligible) go against Him, why He created us?
A man: If I may ask this question.
Dr. Khalifa: That was a very good question, but I think we did go through it before.
Allah Subhanahu Wa Ta'ala (unintelligible) to give us the freedom of choice because if you are able to create robots,
you can create three kinds of robots. One robot will do anything you said.
"Vacuum the house."
It will vacuum the house.
"Wash the dishes." "Yes, sir."
You can also create a robot with a mind.
I mean, "wash the dishes." And it will say "no, I don't wanna wash the dishes."
Or, or "yes." That's the second kind.
The third kind will be the kind with a mind who appreciates you.
So, it appreciates you enough or loves you enough that when you say "vacuum the house", "yes, sir."
Even though he has the choice to say "no."
"Wash the dishes." "Yes, sir."
So, obviously, you will want the third kind. And this is what God willed.
Dr. Khalifa: To create creatures who will serve Him and worship Him with their own, with their own choice, not, not force, not by force.
A man: Right.
A man: So, can you say angels are the robots?
Dr. Khalifa: No, no, no. No, no, no. The angels have freedom of choice.
A man: They have...
Dr. Khalifa: But they appreciated God. They knew God.
And they chose to worship God alone and uphold His Absolute Authority.
Dr. Khalifa: Satan chose not to (unintelligible).
A woman: How we can determine Sheytan (Satan) has an influence on us or not?
Dr. Khalifa: If you do anything that goes against the Quran, this, this is your sign that, that Sheytan (Satan) is, is directing to you.
Anything that... See, Satan has one job,
pushing some other name besides God. This is his only job.
So, if you are devoting your worship to God alone, and you are not concerned with any other names,
this is a sign that you're doing it right.
Dr. Khalifa: The moment any other name comes up, Sheytan (Satan) is in the picture.
A woman: Yes, even when I'm praying, sometimes I'm praying, but it's I'm thinking about some other things like, I have lots of problems.
Dr. Khalifa: No, no, no. A woman: I'm thinking about job or
A woman: I'm thinking about, you know, everything. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A woman: Does that mean Sheytan (Satan) has an influence on me?
Dr. Khalifa: Sometimes Sheytan (Satan) will try to, to whisper (وَسْوَاسِ).
This is why God asked us to seek refuge from the Waswas (وَسْوَاسِ).
Because the whispers in our ears remind us of everything in the world when we get up to Pray.
But don't let this bother you. What, what should be done in the Prayer is that you make sure that from the beginning of the Prayer
to the end of the Prayer, there is no other name except the name of God.
Because the minute you mention any other name, you have committed Shirk.
Shirk means more than one.
And you have disobeyed God, and you have disobeyed the prophet when you mention any other name in the Salat.
This is based on
(20:14) أَقِمِ ٱلصَّلَوٰةَ لِذِكْرِىٓ
which is singular.
[20:14] ... observe the Salat to commemorate Me.
Singular. Even though God speaks in the plural tense in many places in the Quran.
And the other is,
(72:18) وَأَنَّ ٱلْمَسَٰجِدَ لِلَّهِ فَلَا تَدْعُوا۟ مَعَ ٱللَّهِ أَحَدًۭا
[72:18] The places of worship belong to GOD; do not call on anyone else besides GOD.
Dr. Khalifa: So, if anything causes you to mention any other name with God, this will be Satan's order.
A woman: How we can determine if Sheytan (Satan) has influence on us?
Dr. Khalifa: Well, this is what I said, by deviating from God alone.
A woman: I know. I mean, (unintelligible) like for example, I'm, I'm drinking, I'm doing something, I'm smoking, or do
A woman: lots of things wrong. I know it is wrong, but it's my choice. And you said we have a choice, that we can, you know, do this. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A woman: But do I know it's my choice, or is it Sheytan (Satan), or whatever, or is it God or...?
Dr. Khalifa: Well, if you're unhappy for any reason, it is Sheytan (Satan)...
A woman: I'm not unhappy, I'm enjoying it. For example, I'm drinking, I'm enjoying it.
Dr. Khalifa: When you're asking me, I'm answering you.
A woman: I'm asking a question.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah. The answer is, anything that will cause you to put any other name besides God, will be from Sheytan (Satan).
Dr. Khalifa: If you are working, living, doing things, and you're satisfied with God alone, then you (unintelligible) from God.
A woman: Thank you.
A man: Is there any (unintelligible) for the new messenger in Quran?
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, (unintelligible)
First of all, in Sura 3, verse 81, we learn that Allah Subhanahu Wa Ta'ala made a covenant with all the prophets, including the prophet Muhammad
that after they deliver the messages, a messenger will come to confer, consolidate, purify, and unify all the messages.
And this is a clear and straightforward prophecy in the Quran.
The traditionalists and the idol worshippers who praise Muhammad against his will,
they claim that Muhammad was the messenger who will come after all the prophets.
But Allah Subhanahu Wa Ta'ala almost clarifies this in the Quran when we go to Sura 33,
verse 7, we learn that Muhammad was one of the prophets who made that covenant.
So, also, the Quran states that Muhammad is not the last messenger.
Muhammad was the last prophet because he brought the last scripture.
Back to verse 81 in Sura 3, the prophet or Nabi (نبی) is defined as one who is given a book.
(3:81) وَإِذْ أَخَذَ ٱللَّهُ مِيثَٰقَ ٱلنَّبِيِّینَ لَمَآ ءَاتَيْتُكُم مِّن كِتَٰبٍۢ وَحِكْمَةٍۢ
The book or scripture is given to the prophets.
(3:81) ثُمَّ جَآءَكُمْ رَسُولٌۭ مُّصَدِّقٌۭ لِّمَا مَعَكُمْ
For the messenger confirms existing scriptures and does not bring a new scripture.
And the Summa (ثُمَّ) means afterwards.
So, after all the prophets have come, including the prophet Muhammad, as we see in 33:7,
a messenger is supposed to come and consolidate all the messages and confirm them and purify them into one.
Besides this, we go to the statement in Sura 33, verse 40,
which says that Muhammad was not the last messenger but the last prophet because he brought the last scripture.
(33:40) مَّا كَانَ مُحَمَّدٌ أَبَآ أَحَدٍۢ مِّن رِّجَالِكُمْ
[33:40] Muhammad was not the father of any of your man. ...
(33:40) وَلَٰكِن رَّسُولَ ٱللَّهِ [33:40] ... a messenger of God ...
(33:40) وَخَاتَمَ ٱلنَّبِيِّنَ [33:40] ... and the final prophet. ...
If, as some people claim, every Nabi (نبی) was a messenger...
Well, every Nabi (نبی) was a messenger but not every messenger was a prophet.
If the Nabiyeen (نَّبِيِّینَ) includes the Mursaleen (مرسلین), Allah Subhana Wa Ta'ala will not say Rasulullah. He'd say
مَّا كَانَ مُحَمَّدٌ أَبَآ أَحَدٍۢ مِّن رِّجَالِكُمْ
Muhammad was not the father of any of your man.
وَلَٰكِن خَاتَمَ ٱلنَّبِيِّنَ the last prophet.
And this will cover all prophets and the messengers.
But Allah Subhana Wa Ta'ala in the Quran is very accurate, said
(33:40) رَّسُولَ ٱللَّهِ [33:40] ... a messenger of God ...
(33:40) وَخَاتَمَ ٱلنَّبِيِّنَ
So, we learn from this that Muhammad is not the last messenger.
There are many other places in the Quran that have this indication about Rasool (رسول) that says that where it says
(7:35) يَٰبَنِىٓ ءَادَمَ [7:35] O children of Adam,...
(7:35) إِمَّا يَأْتِيَنَّكُمْ رُسُلٌۭ مِّنكُمْ [7:35] ... when messengers come from among you,
(7:35) يَقُصُّونَ عَلَيْكُمْ ءَايَٰتِى reciting our revelations
(7:35) فَمَنِ ٱتَّقَىٰ وَأَصْلَحَ فَلَا خَوْفٌ عَلَيْهِمْ وَلَا هُمْ يَحْزَنُونَ
Obviously, God is not talking to the dead. He's talking to the people in the future, after the Quran.
It said "When messengers come to you, you shall believe and listen."
So, we have this Quranic principle that Muhammad was the last prophet but not the last messenger.
And the verses that come after this, verses 82, 83, 84, 85, 86, 87, 88, 89, 90 and 91,
all these verses say that anyone who rejects this Quranic prophecy is not a Muslim anymore. He's dismissed from God's grace.
And this is what I have in the new issue of the Muslim Perspective but I will give some to Parivash. You can look at it.
So, anyone who, of course, because they do not believe the Quran, anyone who rejects
the premise that Muhammad was not the last messenger, is no longer a believer.
He does not believe God, does not believe the Quran, does not believe the words that came out of Muhammad's mouth.
So, therefore, as believers in the Quran, we must know that Muhammad was not the last messenger.
He was the last prophet because he brought the last scripture.
So, if Muhammad was not the last messenger, and as we see in Sura 3, verse 81, if a messenger is to come after him, what does he look like?
Dr. Khalifa: We have to ask ourselves "what does the messenger look like?"
Dr. Khalifa: Hmm?
A woman: Human being. Dr. Khalifa: Human being.
Dr. Khalifa: What are his qualifications?
What will he advocate?
How can we distinguish the true messenger from the fake messenger?
How do we know if this person is a liar or telling the truth?
So, all these questions must be examined by all of us, as soon as we pass these obstacles.
I have here, if you like, I will give you a sheet that is a step-by-step proof for all these things.
And it begins by the Quranic principle that Muhammad was not the last messenger.
What are the criteria of the true messenger?
How do you tell if the messenger who comes after Muhammad is a true one or a fake one?
We heard of many messengers. People (unintelligible) claiming to be messengers, Joseph Smith, Baha'u'llah,
Ghulam Ahmad, we heard all these people claiming to be messengers.
How can you tell if the messenger is true or fake?
Dr. Khalifa: The criteria... Pardon? Right. A man: Worship God alone.
Dr. Khalifa: The criteria is, first of all, he must advocate the worship of God alone.
Because this is the first commandment in all the scriptures, in all the messages.
And God goes, in the Quran, goes through the messengers, one by one, all of them,
and, and says the same statement after all of them, after each one.
(11:84) يَٰقَوْمِ ٱعْبُدُوا۟ ٱللَّهَ مَا لَكُم مِّنْ إِلَٰهٍ غَيْرُهُ
[11:84] ... "O my people, worship GOD; there are no other god beside Him. ...
The same expression for everyone of the messengers.
Therefore, this is the first criterion.
The true messenger must advocate the worship of God alone.
He must advocate the destruction of all idols and all idol worship.
He must advocate the upholding of the words of God alone, not the words of men, no matter who those men are.
This is your first criterion.
Somebody comes to you and says "I'm a messenger of God."
This is the first judgment that we must, or the first criterion we must satisfy
that this person must be advocating the worship of God alone.
Dr. Khalifa: The second criterion is...
A man: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: This is number 3.
A woman: No.
A man: Yes. Dr. Khalifa: Hmm?
A woman: (unintelligible) A man: Yes. Dr. Khalifa: (unintelligible). Yes. Excuse me.
Dr. Khalifa: He must be supported by a God-given proof.
God says, in the Quran, we demand proof.
(2:111) هَاتُوا۟ بُرْهَٰنَكُمْ
(2:111) قُلْ هَاتُوا۟ بُرْهَٰنَكُمْ
So, a person comes to you and says "I'm a God's messenger." We say "what is your proof?"
The third one is, he doesn't ask for wage for himself.
He doesn't ask you for money.
Because if money enters the picture, it's a whole new issue. So, these are the three criteria.
Advocating the worship of God alone.
Proof from God that he is God's messenger.
Moses came and he threw the staff, became a serpent.
That was the proof from God. There are nine signs, nine miracles.
Jesus revived the dead and healed the blind and the leprous. That was the proof, miracle, from God.
Prophet Muhammad's miracle was the Quran.
So, everyone who comes and claims to be a messenger must have proof.
And third, he must not ask you for money.
If the, if a messenger flunks any of these three criteria, he's not a messenger, he's a liar.
Also, I must emphasize here that the message is the important thing, not the messenger.
As the first generation, in the unified message from Allah Subhanahu Wa Ta'ala, with the purified Quran,
we must destroy all human idols.
This is the first principle. We must be devoted to God alone.
Because the idols themselves do not want to be idolized. Jesus does not want to be idolized.
And as we know from the Quran and from the Bible, he will disown the people who idolize him.
In Matthew 7:21-23, we read that Jesus will say "Many will come to me on the Day of Judgment and tell me, Lord, Lord, did we...
Oh, before that, it says "None of those who call me Lord will make it to Heaven."
"Many of you will come to me and say 'Lord, Lord, have we not prophesied in your name? Have we not performed miracles in your name?'
"Then, I will say to them 'Out of my sight, I don't know you.'"
Jesus will disown them.
And this is also in the Quran.
Muhammad will disown the people who idolize him.
Dr. Khalifa: And we see this in Sura 46. I'm going to read it for you.
Audience: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Got the wrong Sura.
Dr. Khalifa: Listen to this, (unintelligible) these verse.
Dr. Khalifa: Sura 46, verse 4.
No, excuse me, 5. It says,
(46:5) وَمَنْ أَضَلُّ
[46:5] Who is farther astray ...
(46:5) مِمَّن يَدْعُوا۟ مِن دُونِ ٱللَّهِ
who mentions or calls upon besides God.
(46:5) مَن لَّا يَسْتَجِيبُ لَهُۥٓ
one who cannot respond to him.
(46:5) إِلَىٰ يَوْمِ ٱلْقِيَٰمَةِ
[46:5] ... until the Day of Judgement ...
(46:5) وَهُمْ عَن دُعَآئِهِمْ غَٰفِلُونَ
And they are completely unaware of their calling.
(46:6) وَإِذَا حُشِرَ ٱلنَّاسُ
And when the Day of Judgment comes, the Day of Summoning,
(46:6) كَانُوا۟ لَهُمْ أَعْدَآءًۭ
They will become their enemies.
The prophet Muhammad, right now, is dead. As the Quran says,
(39:30) إِنَّكَ مَيِّتٌۭ وَإِنَّهُم مَّيِّتُونَ
He is absolutely unaware of the people who are calling on him, which fits this description.
And on the Day of Judgment, he will be an enemy for people who are calling on him.
And this is where Sheytan (Satan) misleads them and tricks a lot of people in the name of love.
That if you love Muhammad, you have to commemorate him every day.
Muhammad is unaware.
And as we see in these verses, they are the farthest, farthest astray.
I'm going to read it again.
(46:5) وَمَنْ أَضَلُّ
[46:5] Who is farther astray ...
(46:5) مِمَّن يَدْعُوا۟
than those who call upon
(46:5) مِن دُونِ ٱللَّهِ
other than God
(46:5) مَن لَّا يَسْتَجِيبُ
those who cannot respond
(46:5) لَهُۥٓ إِلَىٰ يَوْمِ ٱلْقِيَٰمَةِ
[46:5] ... until the Day of Resurrection, ...
(46:5) وَهُمْ
This is the idols.
(46:5) عَن دُعَآئِهِمْ غَٰفِلُونَ
who are unaware.
Dr. Khalifa: You tell me, is Muhammad aware of the people who are calling on him?
A man: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Muhammad is aware of when you say "please, God (unintelligible) Muhammad (unintelligible)", he is aware?
A man: Allah Subhanahu Wa Ta'ala, by His Mercy, the Quran tells us...
Dr. Khalifa: Is Muhammad dead or alive?
A man: Muhammad is dead but, but
A man: all the Shahids (martyrs) in the Quran, the Shahids (martyrs), not Muhammad, even less human beings, alright, less in Islam,
A man: Shahid (martyr) is any Muslim, Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: who died in God's cause. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: What does the Quran say about the Shahid (martyr)?
(3:169) وَلَا تَحْسَبَنَّ ٱلَّذِينَ قُتِلُوا۟ فِى سَبِيلِ ٱللَّهِ أَمْوَٰتًۢا ۚ بَلْ أَحْيَآءٌ
Parivash: (3:169) عِندَ رَبِّهِمْ يُرْزَقُونَ
A man: (3:169) عِندَ رَبِّهِمْ
Parivash: (3:169) عِندَ رَبِّهِمْ
A man: (3:169) عِندَ رَبِّهِمْ يُرْزَقُونَ
Dr. Khalifa: (unintelligible) عِندَ رَبِّهِمْ
A man: (3:169) عِندَ رَبِّهِمْ
A woman: (3:169) عِندَ رَبِّهِمْ
Parivash: (3:169) عِندَ رَبِّهِمْ
A man: Listen, listen to that.
Dr. Khalifa: Is Muhammad dead or HAY (حَىِّ) (alive)? Is Muhammad MAYYET (مَيِّتٌۭ) (dead) or HAY (حَىِّ) (alive)?
A man: If the Shahid (martyr)...
Dr. Khalifa: Is Muhammad dead or alive?
A man: Muhammad is dead, but Dr. Khalifa: Thank you very much.
A man: (3:169) عِندَ رَبِّهِمْ يُرْزَقُونَ
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: It's all the Shahid (martyr), in the Quran tells us the minute the Shahid (martyr) dies, his body is dead.
A man: You can put him in the grave and you can even, you know, cut him in pieces,
the Shahid (martyr) in front of you. I mean, you take the Shahid (martyr), put him in the casket and put him in the grave.
But Allah says in the Quran that this dead in front of you is not dead.
A man: So, who do we believe, our eyes or the Quran?
Dr. Khalifa: We believe the Quran. The Quran says Muhammad is dead. A man: We believe the Quran.
A man: We believe the Quran.
Dr. Khalifa: It says, Muhammad is dead.
A man: So, Allah Subhanahu Wa Ta'ala says, don't you believe that those people who died in God's cause, he's dead. They are still alive with God.
A man: (3:169) عِندَ رَبِّهِمْ With God.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: And even so I give them food. That means that a human being can be alive with God
A man: even his body is dead in front of you.
Dr. Khalifa: Are they aware of what's happening here?
A man: And, one second, and God is still giving them food.
(3:169) عِندَ رَبِّهِمْ
We don't know where.
Rabbihim (رَبِّهِمْ) is everywhere.
God is everywhere.
A man: So, the Shahid (martyr) is with God.
Dr. Khalifa: Ok. Well, let us, let us show that Muhammad is aware. A man: Where? Everywhere.
A man: So, Muhammad (Sallallahu Alaihi Wa Sallam), he is dead in his body.
A man: But he is one of the Shahid (martyr).
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. A man: He is Nabi (نبی).
A man: He is Rasool (رسول).
A man: He is the high quality even more than the Shahid (martyr).
A man: So, if the Shahid (martyr) with less quality is still alive, Muhammad is still alive.
Dr. Khalifa: Ok. Is he aware of you calling on him?
Dr. Khalifa: Is he aware? Is he aware of your calling on him? A man: Every time
A man: Yes. A woma: Ok.
A man: I'm answering your question.
Dr. Khalifa: You're calling from (unintelligible).
A man: No, I am, I am answering your question. Dr. Khalifa: Yes or No?
A man: I am answering your question.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes or No? Is he aware of your calling on him?
A man: Muhammad is alive. Dr. Khalifa: Yes or No?
Dr. Khalifa: Yes or No? Is Muhammad aware of your calling on him? Or unaware?
A man: I pray to God. God gives him the message.
Audience: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: He is saying that God is Muhammad's secretary.
A man: Allah Subhanahu Wa Ta'ala...
A man: Allah Subhanahu Wa Ta'ala said (3:169) عِندَ رَبِّهِمْ
Audience: (unintelligible)
A man: When you pray to your father, your father is dead. Your father cannot hear you, right?
But Allah Subhanahu Wa Ta'ala takes your prayer from your mouth, give it to your father,
A man: tell him to your father "I have a beautiful gift from your child."
A woman: Where did you get that?
A woman: Where did you find that?
A woman: How did you know that?
Dr. Khalifa: (unintelligible)
A man: So, that's what I'm saying. That's what I'm saying.
A man: If you don't have the Hadith of Rasulullah, you are missing a lot.
A woman: You are saying that Quran is not complete.
A woman: So, that's why (unintelligible) A man: No, I'm saying that Quran is. complete.
A woman: So, you don't mean it is complete. Dr. Khalifa: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: (unintelligible) A woman: You are lying.
A woman: (unintelligible) A man: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Don't tell me that. Is the Quran MOFASSAL (مُفَصَّل) (fully detailed)?
A man: The Quran is MOFASSAL (مُفَصَّل) (fully detailed).
A man: If you read the Quran, I don't remember the Aya, it says that you have to pray for your dead.
Edip: Yes, you know Arabic means fully supported.
A man: I have the dictionary, but I don't have it with me, but (unintelligible).
A man: Can we pray, can we pray for our fathers if he dies or not?
Dr. Khalifa: We're talking about the (unintelligible).
A man: Can we pray?
A woman: It doesn't help him. If God wants to help him...
A man: If God wants,... A woman: It doesn't (unintelligible)
A man: So, if God wants, it will help.
A woman: It really doesn't make any difference because whatever we do, when we are alive...
A man: So, I can pray for him...
A woman: When we die, nobody else can pray for us.
A man: When I pray to God, when I pray to God, God takes my prayer to my father.
A man: When I pray to the prophet Muhammad, God takes my prayer to Muhammad. Dr. Khalifa: No, no, no, no.
A woman: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: No, no. So, Muhammad... he is saying that Muhammad is aware of his calling on him?
A man: God gives him the message. That's what I'm saying.
Edip: God (unintelligible)
A man: God gives the message to everybody.
Dr. Khalifa: God is Muhammad's messenger?
Audience: (unintelligible)
Edip: There are about 400 (unintelligible), is there any (unintelligible)?
A man: The Aya says,
A man: IZA (اذا). IZA (اذا). IZA (اذا)
A woman: You're insulting God.
A man: The Aya says, what it means, if you ask for Allah, Allah is very close to you.
(2:186) إِنِّى قَرِيبٌ ۖ أُجِيبُ دَعْوَةَ ٱلدَّاعِ إِذَا دَعَانِ
A man: If you ask for me, I am very close to you.
A man: And A man: (unintelligible)
A man: So, Allah Subhanahu Wa Ta'ala...
A woman: So, seek God alone. A man: Allah...
A man: No, DA'A (دَعَ). DA'A (دَعَ) means pray for everything. You can pray for a million dollars. You can pray for health. You can pray for somebody to be saved.
A man: You can pray for your dead father to be saved and go to Paradise. Anything you pray for Allah, He's very close to you.
A woman: I mean, if I can pray just for myself to be (unintelligible). Dr. Khalifa: God is saying, God is telling us...
A man: Not for yourself, for your family too. A woman: (unintelligible) that's enough. I mean, (unintelligible).
A woman: And then you say, this one person who can do all, for example, my father, he can do robbery, all the bad things.
A woman: And then, when he dies, I pray to God "please, don't take him to the Hell."
A man: (unintelligible) accepts it from you or not.
A woman: No, everybody is so individual. This is very obvious.
A man: Look, I will tell you just one, one, five seconds story.
A man: One of the imams, one of the imams saw a man stealing an apple, giving it to the poor guy.
A man: He steal an apple from the man, giving it to the poor guy.
A man: So, he went to him... Edip: Hadith, Hadith? Hadith Bukhari. Dr. Khalifa: Yes. No, wait.
Dr. Khalifa: (unintelligible) Hadith.
A man: No, no, no. It's a true story. A man: A true Hadith.
A woman: He said "no." A man: (unintelligible) Hadith.
Audience: (unintelligible)
A man: I am giving you one of the imams, I know him. Alright? I know the imam, by the way.
A man: He saw the guy taking an apple, taking it or stealing it from here, giving it to the poor guy.
A man: He went to him and he said "what did you do?"
A man: He said to him "according to the Quran, I made HASANA (حَسَنَه). So, God will multiply my HASANA (حَسَنَه)."
A man: HASANA (حَسَنَه) means good deed. A woman: Yeah, Ok.
A man: "God will multiply my HASANA (حَسَنَه) which I gave to the poor guy. And I made SAYE'A (سَّيِّئَه) bad deed, so God will excuse me for one bad thing and will give me 10 good things."
A man: "So, I'm winner now. I made 9 out of it." The Imam said to him "what happened is that you stole it, so God writes it for you bad deed, you gave it, God didn't accept it from you. So, you are the loser."
Dr. Khalifa: How did (unintelligible) to accept it like that?
A man: No, he gave him the example, he said, he said "how, how do you know that God is writing it for you? But for sure you are a thief."
A man: And it is because Allah Subhanahu Wa Ta'ala is TAYYIB (طیب). Allah is beautiful, is good thing, He will not accept the Haram (حرام) from you.
Edip: What is the relation between the subjects? The subject is "Muhammad answers your prayer or not?" You said "he answers."
Edip: The Quran says, I want to answer your question, if Muhammad
(46:5) مِن دُونِ ٱللَّهِ
A man: Astaghfirullah al-Azeem
Edip: No, no, no. Is Muhammad other than God?
A man: No, no. A man: He's not God.
A man: He's other than... A man: He's a human like you and I.
Dr. Khalifa: He's other than God.
Edip: Allah says in Quran, chapter...
A man: (unintelligible)
Edip: That's it. 13, chapter 13, verse 14 (unintelligible)
(13:14) وَٱلَّذِينَ يَدْعُونَ مِن دُونِهِ
(13:14) مِن دُونِهِ
in the meaning in this,
everybody. Muhammad also is
(13:14) مِن دُونِهِ
(13:14) وَٱلَّذِينَ يَدْعُونَ مِن دُونِهِۦ لَا يَسْتَجِيبُونَ لَهُم بِشَىْءٍ
Edip: (unintelligible). Muhammad cannot answer because Allah says he cannot answer, ok.
Dr. Khalifa: You put this with the other verse that says,
[46:5] Who is farther astray than those who ...
call on people who cannot respond to them. MAN LA (مَن لَّا). It's the same word.
(46:5) مَن لَّا يَسْتَجِيبُ لَهُۥٓ إِلَىٰ يَوْمِ ٱلْقِيَٰمَةِ
[46:5] Who is farther astray than those who ...
Dr. Khalifa: call upon the people... A man: You are mixing Muhammad and the idols, you know.
Edip: (13:14) مِن دُونِهِ A man: Muhammad (unintelligible)
A man: We're not worshipping Muhammad. Dr. Khalifa: Do you agree, do you agree Muhammad is MIN DUNIHI (مِن دُونِهِ)?
A man: No.
Dr. Khalifa: He's God? Muhammad is God?
A man: He's not God.
Dr. Khalifa: He's MIN DUNILLAH (مِن دُونِ ٱللَّهِ).
A man: MIN DUNILLAH (مِن دُونِ ٱللَّهِ). But we want to call Muhammad.
A man: We never call to ask Muhammad give me money.
A man: I never did that, nobody ever did that.
Dr. Khalifa: You're calling on him.
A man: No, but I say "my Lord, I like you to take me to Paradise, before you take me to paradise, take Muhammad."
A man: ok, this is how much I love him.
A man: That is sufficient (unintelligible).
A man: I love him. I love Muhammad.
A man: I love... I am the man who are, if my father did something good to me,
I love my father and I'm proud to say it. If my father gave me his money, his soul,
A man: his life, I always go everywhere and say "I love my father."
Dr. Khalifa: Do you have doubt that Muhammad (unintelligible)? A man: But if somebody
A man: denies his father and say "my father didn't do anything to me, good deed to me. My father didn't do any good to me", I will assume this guy is arrogant and
A man: he doesn't even appreciate his own father. A woman: No, your father didn't do God's will.
A woman: Your father didn't do God's will.
A man: But I love my father anyway. Dr. Khalifa: I have a question for this fellow here.
Dr. Khalifa: Do you have any doubt that Muhammad has gone to Heaven?
A man: No.
Dr. Khalifa: Do you have any doubt that Muhammad would be in the highest place in Heaven?
Dr. Khalifa: So, why do you ask God to put him in the highest place in Heaven?
A man: I have to.
Dr. Khalifa: (unintelligible) A man: I love him.
Dr. Khalifa: Do you have, do you have any doubt that you're going to Heaven? A man: Yeah.
A man: Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: You have doubt that you're going to Heaven? A man: Yes, I do.
Dr. Khalifa: You're not sure that God will (unintelligible).
Dr. Khalifa: Do you want to go to Heaven? A man: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: So, why don't you pray for yourself? A man: I do.
Dr. Khalifa: Ok. Muhammad, you know, he's going to Heaven, the highest place in Heaven, why do you pray to God?
A man: You think (unintelligible). What? Yeah.
A woman: I have come here. A man: I believe...
A woman: I am a non-believer. I don't believe in Muhammad and I don't believe in God. I have come here to learn.
A woman: I haven't learned anything from this (unintelligible), but I hope that I get to a stage that I can start to believe in something.
A woman: And I don't see any point in (unintelligible).
Dr. Khalifa: You did your job representing Satan.
A woman: Yeah, because he doesn't believe in God.
A woman: I come here, I want to start to learn something.
A man: Yeah.
A woman: I don't think (unintelligible)
A man: Well, you see, you are, you are quoting this thing. There's a fight against Islam.
A man: And you are in presence, you are in the presence now to witness one of the worst historical tragedies
that people fighting Allah in His land, people fighting Islam in the Muslim heart.
A man: They didn't go to the Christians. They came to the Muslims to take Muhammad, to take Jesus, to take Moses, to take Ibrahim.
A woman: She doesn't believe even in God.
A man: That's right. A woman: So, what are you talking about?
A man: No, you came to the wrong place in the wrong time...
A man: That's you.
A man: ... to know about God.
A man: Well, she was here first. A man: You like to know about God,
A man: You like to know about God, I have the (unintelligible).
A woman: (unintelligible)
Audience: (unintelligible)
A man: I believe in God but I think I'm not following on the Shia... A man: Yeah.
A man: And what you guys are talking here, excuse me (unintelligible), just, it's something you guys know very much about
Dr. Khalifa: We don't know anything about it.
A man: We're not using any of these. A woman: (unintelligible)
Audience: (unintelligible)
A woman: You can contact Dr. Khalifa later on and ask your questions. Let everybody else have a chance to talk and know whatever they wanna know while they are here.
A woman: I mean, because you are here, if we wanna hear your (unintelligible). Dr. Khalifa: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: He lied to Parivash telling her, he believed in the miracle of the Quran, he believed as we do, in upholding the Quran alone, in worshipping God alone and when he came here, he's pushing Satan's point of view.
Dr. Khalifa: And he's been lying. A man: I came to meet Dr. Khalifa personally,
A man: to know more what is his message and from the first thing I heard from him, I knew that he is the enemy, the enemy of God, from the minute I saw his face.
A woman: Ok, we don't wanna hear what is your idea.
Audience: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: What is your proof that I am an enemy of God?
A man: Because you calling these people, when I prayed after you, and I'm sorry that I did, this man didn't even say "we love Muhammad" in his prayer, just for one time.
A woman (Speaking Farsi): Guys, let him go.
A man: For one time.
Audience: (unintelligible)
A woman: Don't do it, next time don't do it.
A woman (Speaking Farsi): You have given him a lot of time to speak.
A woman (Speaking Farsi): Where is (unintelligible)?
Edip: Let me finish.
A woman (Speaking Farsi): Open the door so that...
Audience: (unintelligible)
A man: (unintelligible) we know that. What's the difference between the, the real Muslim and the people who pretend they are Muslim?
A man: I'm so glad that he is here, God sent him here to clarify for everybody (unintelligible) how much I was before
A man: because I was before exactly like a Sunni Muslim. Ok. Right now, I am ready to submit to God.
A man: Because I know everything (unintelligible) God. Ok. My professor taught me the mathematics. Yeah, he's a very good man, he helped me, but the subject is mathematics. Ok?
A man: I forgot my professor, I know the mathematics. Muhammad was, I believe Muhammad, I like Muhammad, I like Jesus, I like Moses, but
A man: only thing is Muhammad is with God. The subject is God. Finish.
A man: I'm so glad that he was here, and he showed everybody, what's the difference between a real Muslim, and a very stupid Muslim. Believe me.
A woman: The other thing I like (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Before we pray Maghrib, I have one thing that's very important to share with you, ok.
Dr. Khalifa: This is the most important principle in the Quran, and it says,
(4:48) إِنَّ ٱللَّهَ لَا يَغْفِرُ أَن يُشْرَكَ بِهِۦ وَيَغْفِرُ مَا دُونَ ذَٰلِكَ لِمَن يَشَآءُ
God says that everything is forgivable except SHIRK (شرک).
SHIRK (شرک) means, if you have a business, and you are the only owner, this is so called assault proprietorship.
If you have somebody else with you, this is SHIRK (شرک), you have a SHARIK (شریک).
And God says that the only unforgivable offense, the only one, is SHIRK (شرک).
Therefore, if you want to guarantee to go to Heaven, or if you commemorate and devote yourself and the worship to God alone,
you will not commit this SHIRK (شرک), the only unforgivable offense. An intelligent person will say
"if this is the only unforgivable offense, I will run away from the slightest suspicion of SHIRK (شرک)",
of putting anything with God, no matter who that anything is, or what that anything is,
because this is the only unforgivable offense. Now, this fellow here is pushing the name of Muhammad.
That is not the name of God. We are talking about God alone. He is saying "put Muhammad with God."
This is, this may not be SHIRK (شرک). Maybe, it is not SHIRK (شرک). Maybe, it is perfectly alright.
But it's also "maybe." This is a maybe. It may be SHIRK (شرک). Therefore, you can take a chance
and pray to Muhammad, or to Jesus, or Hussein, or whatever you want and then find out on the Day of Judgement
whether it is maybe right or wrong, but what is absolutely sure to be correct is devotion to God alone
because God repeats in the Quran, repeats this verse.
(4:48) إِنَّ ٱللَّهَ لَا يَغْفِرُ أَن يُشْرَكَ بِهِۦ
God does not forgive the putting of someone next to Him, with Him.
(4:48) وَيَغْفِرُ مَا دُونَ ذَٰلِكَ لِمَن يَشَآءُ
So, the thing that is absolutely guaranteed to be correct, is "La Elaha Ella Allah"
and devotion to God alone. God... Sura 29, Sura 29 says,
God is the One who created you. God is the One who provides for you. God is the One who...
(29:19) ٱللَّهُ ٱلْخَلْقَ ثُمَّ يُعِيدُهُۥٓ
who decides your life or death. God is the One who resurrects you. God is the One who will put you in Heaven or Hell.
Muhammad has no role here. He did not create you, had no role in creating you. He has no role in providing for you. He has no role in deciding your life.
He has no role in resurrecting you. He has no role in putting you in Heaven or Hell.
In Sura 54, we read that God is the One who makes you happy or miserable.
(53:43) وَأَنَّهُۥ هُوَ أَضْحَكَ وَأَبْكَىٰ
God is the One who makes you rich or poor.
(53:48) وَأَنَّهُۥ هُوَ أَغْنَىٰ وَأَقْنَىٰ
Muhammad has no role in this.
So, an intelligent person will look at this law which is that God forgives everything except SHIRK (شرک) and will run away
as fast as he can from the slightest suspicion of SHIRK (شرک) because this is the only guarantee there.
And as you witnessed tonight, God sent this man, he's God-sent to show you how the traditional Muslims push another name with God
Dr. Khalifa: which is the only unforgivable sin.
A woman: I'd like to add something that we have the great honor for not only Muhammad
but the other messengers as well and that's by showing that we are following his path.
I mean, the way we are doing the Salat and the Zakat and the Fasting and all the other rules and regulations that God has asked us to do
that shows that we are following the book which has been revealed to Muhammad
by God and this is a great respect and honor. So, that doesn't mean what you say
that we hate Muhammad or we, we kind of dishonor him or disrespect him. This is not true at all.
A woman: Like the other things that you said which was not true.
Dr. Khalifa: Respecting Muhammad is respecting the word that came out of his mouth and obeying it. A woman: Of course.
Dr. Khalifa: These are the first people who disobeyed the prophet.
And God tells us in Sura 25 verse 30,
(25:30) وَقَالَ ٱلرَّسُولُ يَٰرَبِّ إِنَّ قَوْمِى ٱتَّخَذُوا۟ هَٰذَا ٱلْقُرْءَانَ مَهْجُورًۭا
Dr. Khalifa: That the prophet, prophet Muhammad is saddened and upset and embarrassed on the Day of Judgement. He would say,
[25:30] ...my people have deserted this Quran."
A man: Not Bukhari.
Dr. Khalifa: Because they go to Bukhari and he didn't say,
يَٰرَبِّ إِنَّ قَوْمِى ٱتَّخَذُوا۟ الحدیث و السنه مَهْجُورًۭا
or
يَٰرَبِّ إِنَّ قَوْمِى ٱتَّخَذُوا۟ البخاری مَهْجُورًۭا
He said,
(25:30) يَٰرَبِّ إِنَّ قَوْمِى ٱتَّخَذُوا۟ هَٰذَا ٱلْقُرْءَانَ مَهْجُورًۭا
A man: The miracle of the, the miracle of the Sunnah of Rasool Allah is one thing
that nobody can Pray 2 times in Fajr and 4 and 4 and 3 and 4 from the Quran alone.
A man: There's nothing in the Quran here... Dr. Khalifa: You're telling God is a liar?
A man: There's nothing, nothing in the Quran here say Dr. Khalifa: You're said the Quran is (unintelligible).
A man: "Pray 2 Rak'at for Al-Fajr, 4 Rak'at Zohr, 4 Rak'at Al-'Asr, 3 Maghrib, 4 Al-'Esha." Nothing in the Quran say that.
A man: And where do you have it? Dr. Khalifa: Ok, wait a minute here. This is the,
Dr. Khalifa: This is the result of ignorance of the Quran.
A man: Tell me where do you have it?
Dr. Khalifa: Because God says
(6:114) أَفَغَيْرَ ٱللَّهِ أَبْتَغِى حَكَمًۭا وَهُوَ ٱلَّذِىٓ أَنزَلَ إِلَيْكُمُ ٱلْكِتَٰبَ مُفَصَّلًۭا
Dr. Khalifa: God says the Quran is MUFASALAN (مُفَصَّلًۭا), fully detailed.
A man: Where do you have it?
Dr. Khalifa: He says,
(12:111) مَا كَانَ حَدِيثًۭا يُفْتَرَىٰ
Dr. Khalifa: This is not fabricated Hadith.
(12:111) وَلَٰكِن تَصْدِيقَ ٱلَّذِى بَيْنَ يَدَيْهِ وَتَفْصِيلَ كُلِّ شَىْءٍۢ
Dr. Khalifa: Detailing everything.
Dr. Khalifa: Now, these people do not believe God when He says the Quran is MUFASALAN (مُفَصَّلًۭا).
(12:111) تَفْصِيلَ كُلِّ شَىْءٍۢ
It's fully detailed.
They challenge God and say "show me where does it say the Noon is 4 Rak'at."
Ok. This is challenging God. In other words, he's saying
"ok God, You claim that this book is fully detailed. If You are right, God, show me where does it get the details of Salat?"
And this blasphemous question is the result of ignorance because the Quran says that the Salat
was in existence before the Quran, that the Salat, the Zakat, the Hajj and all these things came through Ibrahim.
Islam is not Millat (مِّلَّةَ) Muhammad. It is not. He doesn't know that. It's ignorance of the Quran that causes these disasters.
This religion, Islam, is called throughout the Quran is called Millat Ibrahim (مِّلَّةَ إِبْرَٰهِيمَ).
وَقَالُوا۟ كُونُوا۟ هُودًا أَوْ نَصَٰرَىٰ تَهْتَدُوا۟ ۗ قُلْ بَلْ مِلَّةَ إِبْرَٰهِیمَ (2:135) حَنِيفًۭا
(4:125) وَمَنْ أَحْسَنُ دِينًۭا مِّمَّنْ أَسْلَمَ ... مِلَّةَ إِبْرَٰهِيمَ
And then, the Quran says that Muhammad was following Millat Ibrahim (مِلَّةَ إِبْرَٰهِیمَ).
ثُمَّ أَوْحَيْنَآ إِلَيْكَ أَنِ ٱتَّبِعْ مِلَّةَ إِبْرَٰهِيمَ حَنِيفًۭا ۖ وَمَا كَانَ مِنَ (16:123) ٱلْمُشْرِكِينَ
So, the prophet Muhammad is a follower of Millat Ibrahim (مِلَّةَ إِبْرَٰهِیمَ). The Quran says in many places which he's not aware of
that the Salat existed before the Quran. Therefore, the things... in Sura 22, the last verse says,
(22:78) وَجَٰهِدُوا۟ فِى ٱللَّهِ حَقَّ جِهَادِهِ
Strive in the cause of God.
(22:78) هُوَ ٱجْتَبَىٰكُمْ
He chose you
(22:78) وَمَا جَعَلَ عَلَيْكُمْ فِى ٱلدِّينِ مِنْ حَرَجٍۢ
and did not cause any difficulty in your religion
(22:78) مِّلَّةَ أَبِيكُمْ إِبْرَٰهِيمَ
This is the religion of your father Ibrahim.
(22:78) هُوَ سَمَّىٰكُمُ ٱلْمُسْلِمِينَ مِن قَبْلُ
This fellow here insulted Muhammad and he does not realize that before Muhammad there was life.
Dr. Khalifa: He does not realize. He think life started with Muhammad. A man: He didn't answer my question.
A man: He didn't answer my question. A woman: He answered your question.
Dr. Khalifa: So, therefore, if you read Sura 21, verse 73, we know that the Salat and Zakat and all the duties came through Ibrahim.
(21:73) وَأَوْحَيْنَآ إِلَيْهِمْ فِعْلَ ٱلْخَيْرَٰتِ وَإِقَامَ ٱلصَّلَوٰةِ وَإِيتَآءَ ٱلزَّكَوٰةِ
And we see in the Quran people who did not believe. They rejected Muhammad, and they were doing the Salat and Zakat.
(9:54) وَمَا مَنَعَهُمْ أَن تُقْبَلَ مِنْهُمْ نَفَقَٰتُهُمْ
what prevented the acceptance of their worship...